<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Simon Jürgensmeyer</title>
    <link>https://sj14.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Simon Jürgensmeyer</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>Simon.Juergensmeyer@gmail.com (Simon Jürgensmeyer)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>Simon.Juergensmeyer@gmail.com (Simon Jürgensmeyer)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 10:13:20 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://sj14.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-Time Anomaly Detection in Time Series Data Streams</title>
      <link>https://sj14.github.io/post/anomaly-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 10:13:20 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Simon.Juergensmeyer@gmail.com (Simon Jürgensmeyer)</author>
      <guid>https://sj14.github.io/post/anomaly-detection/</guid>
      <description>Description
The research goal of my master thesis was to find real-time capable solutions to automatically detect anomalies in time series data streams, which are especially useful to monitor servers. I evaluated several algorithms and finally ensembled an own algorithm which meets almost all of the previously gathered requirements.
In the figure, you can see a collection of outliers, the algorithm is so good, it is even hard to see the anomaly behind all the true positives (green dots) ;-) At the beginning of the measurements, there are two false positives (red dots)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prototyping a Computer Algebra System in Go</title>
      <link>https://sj14.github.io/post/computer-algebra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 10:13:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Simon.Juergensmeyer@gmail.com (Simon Jürgensmeyer)</author>
      <guid>https://sj14.github.io/post/computer-algebra/</guid>
      <description>Description
It was time for my bachelor thesis and I was thinking about the topic. At this time I was totally hyped by Go (and I&amp;rsquo;m still), so I wanted to find something related. As I am always curious how things work, I wanted to research a calculator with simple algebraic operations and a web interface based on Bootstrap. Of course, this was highly inspired by all students favourite Wolfram Alpha ;-)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android App: Notification To Speech</title>
      <link>https://sj14.github.io/post/notification-to-speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 10:13:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Simon.Juergensmeyer@gmail.com (Simon Jürgensmeyer)</author>
      <guid>https://sj14.github.io/post/notification-to-speech/</guid>
      <description>Description
At the very beginning of my CS studies, I played a bit with Android development. You achieve the most learning when you are interested in the stuff you are doing or you have own requirements. My motivation was to write an app, which can speak out incoming notifications. As a text-to-speech engine was already built into Android (e.g. navigation directions), I thought this was a challenging but possible project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geoinformatics and QGIS</title>
      <link>https://sj14.github.io/post/geoinformatic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 10:13:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>Simon.Juergensmeyer@gmail.com (Simon Jürgensmeyer)</author>
      <guid>https://sj14.github.io/post/geoinformatic/</guid>
      <description>Description
One of my courses during the master studies was geoinformatics. Hm, how can I describe geoinformatics with a single sentence? Without being too accurate: Everything behind services like Google Maps or OpenStreetMap, and more :D
During the course, we learned all the fundamentals, for example how GPS works. Another topic is the many geographic reference systems and projections. There are so many, mainly because there isn&amp;rsquo;t a perfect solution to map a kind of a globe onto a 2-dimensional picture, thus for several use-cases, there are other approaches to deal with the distortions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://sj14.github.io/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>Simon.Juergensmeyer@gmail.com (Simon Jürgensmeyer)</author>
      <guid>https://sj14.github.io/page/about/</guid>
      <description>About Me Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Simon, a passionate software developer from Germany. I love programming with Go and playing with Unix-like operating systems.
I will use this blog to show some of my projects. Maybe I will add some small tutorials or findings later on &amp;ndash; when I find some time between all my work ;-)
Curriculum Vitae University Mar. 2016 - Jan. 2018 Rhein-Waal University of Applied Sciences
Information Engineering &amp;amp; Computer Science</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>